[
    {
        "question": "Electricity may be generated by a wire:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "carrying current",
        "b": "wrapped as a coil",
        "c": "that has neutral domains",
        "d": "passing through a flux field",
        "answer": "passing through a flux field"
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq11_1006_1.gifIn the given circuit, what will the voltage be across R3 25 mu.gifs after the switch is moved to position 2?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "2.88 V",
        "b": "5.9 V",
        "c": "8.34 V",
        "d": "14 V",
        "answer": "5.9 V"
    },
    {
        "question": "The electrical energy consumed by a coil is stored in the form of:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "an electrical field",
        "b": "a force field",
        "c": "an electrostatic field",
        "d": "a magnetic field",
        "answer": "a magnetic field"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is magnetic flux?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "the number of lines of force in webers",
        "b": "the number of lines of force in maxwells",
        "c": "the number of lines of force in teslas",
        "d": "the number of lines of force in flux density",
        "answer": "the number of lines of force in webers"
    },
    {
        "question": "As current travels within a conductor:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "the magnetic field aids the current",
        "b": "a magnetic field is developed around it",
        "c": "the wire tries to point north",
        "d": "an electrostatic field opposes the current",
        "answer": "a magnetic field is developed around it"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of device consists of a coil with a moveable iron core?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "solenoid",
        "b": "reed switch",
        "c": "relay",
        "d": "armature",
        "answer": "solenoid"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is hysteresis?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "lead between cause and effect",
        "b": "lag between cause and effect",
        "c": "lead between voltage and current",
        "d": "lag between voltage and current",
        "answer": "lag between cause and effect"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a purely inductive circuit,\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "current leads voltage by 90\u00b0",
        "b": "voltage lags current by 90\u00b0",
        "c": "voltage leads current by 90\u00b0",
        "d": "voltage and current are in phase (0\u00b0)",
        "answer": "voltage leads current by 90\u00b0"
    },
    {
        "question": "A series RL filter circuit with an output across the inductor will result in what type of filtering?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "passing of the higher frequencies",
        "b": "passing of the lower frequencies",
        "c": "blocking of the higher frequencies",
        "d": "blocking of a certain range of frequencies",
        "answer": "passing of the higher frequencies"
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq11_1004_1.gifWhat is the total inductance in the given circuit?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "160 mH",
        "b": "300 mH",
        "c": "900 mH",
        "d": "1700 mH",
        "answer": "160 mH"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a schematic, dashed lines between two vertical coils usually mean the transformer has:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "an air core",
        "b": "an iron core",
        "c": "a nonmetallic core",
        "d": "a ferrite core",
        "answer": "a ferrite core"
    },
    {
        "question": "Faraday's law states that the:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "direction of the induced voltage produces an opposition",
        "b": "direction of an induced current produces an aiding effect",
        "c": "emf depends on the rate of cutting flux",
        "d": "emf is related to the direction of the current",
        "answer": "emf depends on the rate of cutting flux"
    },
    {
        "question": "A henry value divided by a circuit resistive value provides the:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "counter emf value",
        "b": "induced voltage amplitude",
        "c": "rise or decay time constant",
        "d": "quality factor of the coil",
        "answer": "induced voltage amplitude"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does Faraday's law concern?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "a magnetic field in a coil",
        "b": "a magnetic field cutting a conductor",
        "c": "a magnetic field hystersis",
        "d": "a magnetic field in a conductor",
        "answer": "a magnetic field cutting a conductor"
    },
    {
        "question": "The polarity of induced voltage while a field is collapsing is:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "independent of the force creating it",
        "b": "opposite to the force creating it",
        "c": "identical to the force creating the field",
        "d": "present only if the force is stationary",
        "answer": "opposite to the force creating it"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the permeability of transformer iron?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "50",
        "b": "450",
        "c": "1,500",
        "d": "5,500",
        "answer": "5,500"
    },
    {
        "question": "Electromagnetism is the:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "magnetic field caused by a permanent magnet",
        "b": "action between a permanent and an artificial magnet",
        "c": "magnetic field action with a current-carrying wire",
        "d": "current in the coil",
        "answer": "magnetic field action with a current-carrying wire"
    },
    {
        "question": "A magnetic field has:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "polar fields",
        "b": "lines of force",
        "c": "magnetomotive force",
        "d": "lines of reluctance",
        "answer": "lines of force"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which two values are plotted on a B-H curve graph?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "reluctance and flux density",
        "b": "permeability and reluctance",
        "c": "magnetizing force and permeability",
        "d": "flux density and magnetizing force",
        "answer": "flux density and magnetizing force"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the number of turns required in the secondary winding for a transformer when 120 volts is applied to a 2400-turn primary to produce 7.5 Vac at the secondary?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "75 turns",
        "b": "150 turns",
        "c": "900 turns",
        "d": "1920 turns",
        "answer": "150 turns"
    },
    {
        "question": "The four factors determining inductance are the number of turns, coil length, coil area, and:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "permeability",
        "b": "reluctance",
        "c": "counter emf",
        "d": "coefficient of coupling",
        "answer": "permeability"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the inductive reactance if the Q of a coil is 60, and the winding resistance is 5 ohm?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "0.083 ohm",
        "b": "12 ohm",
        "c": "30 ohm",
        "d": "300 ohm",
        "answer": "300 ohm"
    },
    {
        "question": "The time difference, or lag, between flux density and magnetizing force is known as:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "eddy current",
        "b": "magnetic saturation",
        "c": "hysteresis",
        "d": "coercivity",
        "answer": "hysteresis"
    },
    {
        "question": "A magnetic circuit breaker will open to protect equipment only when:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "voltage is exceeded",
        "b": "an open is in the equipment",
        "c": "the equipment is operating properly",
        "d": "current is exceeded",
        "answer": "current is exceeded"
    },
    {
        "question": "Electromagnetic induction is the generation of:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "electricity from magnetism",
        "b": "electricity from electricity",
        "c": "magnetism from electricity",
        "d": "magnetism from magnetism",
        "answer": "electricity from magnetism"
    },
    {
        "question": "Inductance ",
        "a": "directly proportional to the length of the coil",
        "b": "directly proportional to the number of turns on the coil",
        "c": "inversely proportional to the cross-sectional area of the coil",
        "d": "inversely proportional to the permeability",
        "answer": "directly proportional to the number of turns on the coil"
    },
    {
        "question": "Current will cause a magnetic field in a conductor as follows:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "An ac current causes a fixed polarity magnetic field.",
        "b": "A dc current causes a fixed polarity magnetic field.",
        "c": "A dc current causes an alternating magnetic field.",
        "d": "An ac current causes a fixed polarity magnetic field and a dc current causes an alternating magnetic field.",
        "answer": "A dc current causes a fixed polarity magnetic field."
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq8_1030_1.gifWhat is the total inductance, assuming no mutual inductance?\r\n",
        "a": "12 mH",
        "b": "6 mH",
        "c": "0.73 mH",
        "d": "0 mH",
        "answer": "12 mH"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a current change, the ability of a conductor to produce counter emf within itself is called:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "back emf",
        "b": "self-induction",
        "c": "a henry",
        "d": "impedance",
        "answer": "self-induction"
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq11_1006_1.gifIf the switch is moved to position 1 in the given circuit, how long will it take for the current to reach its maximum value?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "72.5 us",
        "b": "532 us",
        "c": "610 us",
        "d": "833 us",
        "answer": "532 us"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a transformer secondary lead has been connected to a middle loop that is not an end connector, it is called a:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "multiple-tapped secondary",
        "b": "center-tapped secondary",
        "c": "multiple winding secondary",
        "d": "single winding secondary",
        "answer": "center-tapped secondary"
    },
    {
        "question": "A 24 V peak source is connected across a 900 uH inductor. If the frequency of the source is 22 kHz, what is the reactive power?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "2.3 VAR",
        "b": "4.6 VAR",
        "c": "9.3 VAR",
        "d": "0 VAR",
        "answer": "2.3 VAR"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the permeability of machine steel?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "1.1 x 10^\u22124",
        "b": "5.65 x 10^\u22124",
        "c": "6.9 x 10^\u22123",
        "d": "8.8 x 10^\u22123",
        "answer": "5.65 x 10^\u22124"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will happen when an inductor's magnetic field collapses?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Current will double.",
        "b": "Voltage will be induced.",
        "c": "A new field will expand.",
        "d": "Counter emf will be high.",
        "answer": "Voltage will be induced."
    },
    {
        "question": "With a square wave input, an RL differentiator circuit with an output across the inductor will produce what type of waveform?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "dc",
        "b": "short time-duration pulses",
        "c": "exponential-shaped pulses",
        "d": "only a phase shift",
        "answer": "short time-duration pulses"
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq8_1032_1.gifHow long until the current is at a maximum?\r\n",
        "a": " 0 us",
        "b": "5 us",
        "c": "15 us",
        "d": "25 us",
        "answer": "5 us"
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq8_1034_1.gifFind VR and VL.\r\n",
        "a": "VR = 41.6 V, VL = 78.4 V",
        "b": "VR = 48 V, VL = 110 V",
        "c": "VR = 56 V, VL = 106 V",
        "d": "VR = 60 V, VL = 60 V",
        "answer": "VR = 56 V, VL = 106 V"
    },
    {
        "question": "If 360 Vac is the output of a 300-turn secondary winding, what is the input voltage when the primary winding has 150 turns?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "2.4 Vac",
        "b": "150 Vac",
        "c": "180 Vac",
        "d": "720 Vac",
        "answer": "180 Vac"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a magnet enters a coil and a voltage is induced, the process is known as:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "an alternation",
        "b": "self-inductance",
        "c": "counter emf",
        "d": "flux linkage",
        "answer": "flux linkage"
    },
    {
        "question": "What term is used to describe the action of magnetic flux from one circuit that cuts across the conductors of another circuit?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "self-inductance",
        "b": "rectification",
        "c": "mutual inductance",
        "d": "magnetism",
        "answer": "mutual inductance"
    },
    {
        "question": "Reactance in an inductive circuit will:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "increase with frequency",
        "b": "decrease with frequency",
        "c": "be independent from frequency",
        "d": "depend on the value of Xc",
        "answer": "increase with frequency"
    },
    {
        "question": "A turns ratio of 5 for a transformer implies:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "more primary turns than secondary turns",
        "b": "more secondary current than primary current",
        "c": "larger source impedance than load impedance",
        "d": "more secondary turns than primary turns",
        "answer": "more secondary turns than primary turns"
    },
    {
        "question": "A practical inductor\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "has inductance",
        "b": "has winding resistance",
        "c": "has winding capacitance",
        "d": "all of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "When current in an inductor starts to change, it cannot react instantly due to:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "fixed coil resistance",
        "b": "eddy current generation",
        "c": "applied emf of the circuit",
        "d": "the counter emf of the coil",
        "answer": "the counter emf of the coil"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the approximate time for a complete decay of 400 mA of inductor current, when R = 10 ohms and L = 20 H?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "10 seconds",
        "b": "8 seconds",
        "c": "4 seconds",
        "d": "2 seconds",
        "answer": "10 seconds"
    },
    {
        "question": "A utility pole transformer used to supply a residential customer with two phases uses:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "two phases on the primary",
        "b": "a center tap on the secondary",
        "c": "a separate ground for each phase",
        "d": "a small coefficient of coupling",
        "answer": "a center tap on the secondary"
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq8_1033_1.gifWhat is the inductive reactance?\r\n",
        "a": "5.2 ohm",
        "b": "7.5 ohm",
        "c": "1.3 k ohm",
        "d": "7.5 k ohm",
        "answer": "7.5 k ohm"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a coil collapses the induced circuit current will:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "be in the same direction",
        "b": "go to zero",
        "c": "aid counter emf buildup",
        "d": "be in the opposite direction",
        "answer": "be in the same direction"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a rate of one ampere per second causes an induced voltage of one volt, the unit of measure is\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "a lenz",
        "b": "an ohm",
        "c": "a farad",
        "d": "a henry",
        "answer": "a henry"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you wanted to decrease the inductance of a coil, you might increase the:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "number of turns",
        "b": "permeability of the core",
        "c": "spacing between turns",
        "d": "area of the coil",
        "answer": "spacing between turns"
    },
    {
        "question": "The output phase for a transformer is:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "in phase with the input",
        "b": "out of phase with the input",
        "c": "dependent on the direction of the primary and secondary windings",
        "d": "dependent on the frequency of the primary source",
        "answer": "dependent on the direction of the primary and secondary windings"
    },
    {
        "question": "Opposition to current flow without the dissipation of energy is called:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "resistance",
        "b": "inductive reactance",
        "c": "counter emf",
        "d": "impedance",
        "answer": "inductive reactance"
    },
    {
        "question": "With 100 Vac applied to the primary of a transformer so that it draws 500 mA, what will be the 300 Vac secondary current?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "1500 mA",
        "b": "200 mA",
        "c": "167 mA",
        "d": "150 mA",
        "answer": "167 mA"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which coil would be used as a step-up transformer primary if coil number 1 has 100 more turns than coil number 2?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "The coil windings must be the same.",
        "b": "coil 1",
        "c": "The coil ratio is too small.",
        "d": "coil 2",
        "answer": "coil 2"
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq8_1035_1.gifFind IR and IL.\r\n",
        "a": "IR = 50 mA, IL = 109 mA",
        "b": "IR = 150 mA, IL = 9 mA",
        "c": "IR = 50 mA, IL = 151 mA",
        "d": "IR = 150 mA, IL = 53 mA",
        "answer": "IR = 150 mA, IL = 53 mA"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the transformer secondary is not loaded:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "secondary voltage increases",
        "b": "no secondary current flows",
        "c": "no secondary voltage is present",
        "d": "secondary current increases",
        "answer": "no secondary current flows"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the current rise after 2 time constants if Vs = 12 V dc, R = 60 ohm, and the inductor is rated at 24 mH?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "79.9 mA",
        "b": "126.4 mA",
        "c": "173.0 mA",
        "d": "198.6 mA",
        "answer": "173.0 mA"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the total inductance of a 5 H and a 100 mH coil connected in parallel?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "4.76 mH",
        "b": "33.3 mH",
        "c": "98.0 mH",
        "d": "150.0 mH",
        "answer": "98.0 mH"
    },
    {
        "question": "A transformer is used:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "to couple electric energy from one dc circuit to another",
        "b": "to couple electric energy from an ac circuit to a dc circuit",
        "c": "to couple electric energy from a dc circuit to an ac circuit",
        "d": "to couple electric energy from one ac circuit to another",
        "answer": "to couple electric energy from one ac circuit to another"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of the three major types of fixed inductor?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "air core",
        "b": "ferrite core",
        "c": "magnesium core",
        "d": "iron core",
        "answer": "magnesium core"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the impedance of a 1 kHz series RL circuit when R and XL are both 1000 ohms?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "500 ohms",
        "b": "1000 ohms",
        "c": "1414 ohms",
        "d": "2000 ohms",
        "answer": "1414 ohms"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is remanence?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "reactance",
        "b": "reluctance",
        "c": "retentitivity",
        "d": "resistance",
        "answer": "retentitivity"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an electromagnet reaches maximum strength, it is considered to be:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "in field condition",
        "b": "at saturation",
        "c": "inhibited",
        "d": "at field strength",
        "answer": "at saturation"
    },
    {
        "question": "You could decrease the time constant of an RL circuit by\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "adding a resistor in parallel with the circuit resistance",
        "b": "adding an inductor in series with the circuit inductance",
        "c": "decreasing the amplitude of the input voltage",
        "d": "exchanging the position of the resistor and inductor in the circuit",
        "answer": "adding an inductor in series with the circuit inductance"
    },
    {
        "question": "Indication of transformer primary and secondary voltage relationships is accomplished by:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "color-coded wires",
        "b": "dot notation",
        "c": "black, rather than gray, casings",
        "d": "winding ratios",
        "answer": "dot notation"
    },
    {
        "question": "As a generator armature passes the 270 degree point, the induced voltage is:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "at maximum negative",
        "b": "between maximum negative and zero",
        "c": "at maximum positive",
        "d": "between zero and maximum positive",
        "answer": "at maximum negative"
    },
    {
        "question": "A value of \"ten to the eighth power magnetic lines of force\" is for the term:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "field",
        "b": "flux",
        "c": "coulomb",
        "d": "weber",
        "answer": "weber"
    },
    {
        "question": "A change of one ampere per second in an inductor that induces a voltage of one volt is considered as which unit value?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "a lenz",
        "b": "an ohm",
        "c": "a farad",
        "d": "a henry",
        "answer": "a henry"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the part inside a relay that is moved by the action of the electromagnet?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "armature",
        "b": "conductor",
        "c": "contacts",
        "d": "solenoid",
        "answer": "armature"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the primary of a 4:1 turns transformer dissipates 5 W, what is the secondary power?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "5.0 W",
        "b": "1.25 pW",
        "c": "9.5 W",
        "d": "20.0 mW",
        "answer": "5.0 W"
    },
    {
        "question": "The unit of flux density is:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "magnetomotive force",
        "b": "a weber",
        "c": "a maxwell",
        "d": "a tesla",
        "answer": "a tesla"
    },
    {
        "question": "When used as a filter, an inductor is\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "placed in series with the load and aids any current changes",
        "b": "placed in parallel with the load and aids any current changes",
        "c": "placed in parallel with the load and opposes any current changes",
        "d": "placed in series with the load and opposes any current changes",
        "answer": "placed in series with the load and opposes any current changes"
    },
    {
        "question": "A loaded transformer will achieve mutual induction when:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "secondary current increase causes a primary current decrease",
        "b": "primary current is increased by an increase in secondary current",
        "c": "primary current is decreased by an increase in secondary current",
        "d": "secondary current decrease causes a primary current increase",
        "answer": "primary current is increased by an increase in secondary current"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which transformer turns ratio is needed to match two 16-ohm parallel devices to an output of 22.2 ohms?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "1.38:1",
        "b": "1.67:1",
        "c": "0.72:1",
        "d": "0.60:1",
        "answer": "0.60:1"
    },
    {
        "question": "A transformer will have:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "primary and secondary windings",
        "b": "primary and secondary current",
        "c": "primary wattage producing secondary current",
        "d": "different frequencies for the primary and secondary",
        "answer": "primary and secondary windings"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the phase angle of a 24 Vac parallel RL circuit when R = 45 ohms and XL = 1100 ohms?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "0.001 degrees",
        "b": "2.300 degrees",
        "c": "87.600 degrees",
        "d": "89.900 degrees",
        "answer": "2.300 degrees"
    },
    {
        "question": "A winding of wire can be called\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "an inductor",
        "b": "a coil",
        "c": "a choke",
        "d": "All of the above",
        "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "What happens when moving expanding lines of force encounter a conductor?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Current increases.",
        "b": "Voltage is induced.",
        "c": "Resistance is reduced.",
        "d": "Power is increased.",
        "answer": "Voltage is induced."
    },
    {
        "question": "Fixed transformers have:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "a center-tapped secondary",
        "b": "multiple windings",
        "c": "turns ratios that cannot be changed",
        "d": "a multiple-tapped secondary",
        "answer": "turns ratios that cannot be changed"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following represents a true equivalent of an inductor?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "An inductance in series with a resistance and a capacitance",
        "b": "A capacitance in parallel with the series combination of a resistance and an inductance",
        "c": "An inductance in parallel with the series combination of a resistance and a capacitance",
        "d": "The only quality a real inductor has is inductance.",
        "answer": "A capacitance in parallel with the series combination of a resistance and an inductance"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a transformer, what will happen to the primary current if the secondary magnetic field increases?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Ip will increase.",
        "b": "Ip will be canceled.",
        "c": "Ip will remain the same.",
        "d": "Ip will decrease.",
        "answer": "Ip will increase."
    },
    {
        "question": "The time required for one weber of flux to cut a conductor and produce one volt is:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "one revolution",
        "b": "one second",
        "c": "one millisecond",
        "d": "four revolutions",
        "answer": "one second"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum source current for a transformer rated at 10 kVA, 1000\/500 60 Hz?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "2 A",
        "b": "5 A",
        "c": "10 A",
        "d": "20 A",
        "answer": "20 A"
    },
    {
        "question": "mcq8_1031_1.gifWhat is the total inductance assuming no mutual inductance?\r\n",
        "a": "0 mH",
        "b": "0.69 mH",
        "c": "12 mH",
        "d": "24 mH",
        "answer": "0.69 mH"
    },
    {
        "question": "A voltage is induced in a transformer secondary winding by the action of the:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "secondary magnetic field",
        "b": "primary turns ratio",
        "c": "primary magnetic field",
        "d": "secondary counter emf",
        "answer": "primary magnetic field"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is electromagnetism?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "the magnetic field generated around a conductor when a current passes through it",
        "b": "the magnetic field generated in a conductor by an external voltage",
        "c": "the voltage caused by a magnetic field in a conductor",
        "d": "the current generated by an external magnetic field",
        "answer": "the magnetic field generated around a conductor when a current passes through it"
    },
    {
        "question": "Counter emf or induced voltage is:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "inversely proportional to the change in current",
        "b": "directly proportional to the change in time",
        "c": "directly proportional to the inductance in henrys",
        "d": "inversely proportional to the inductance in henrys",
        "answer": "directly proportional to the inductance in henrys"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the properties that determine the inductance of a coil?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "Length of wire, number of turns, type of core material, length of core",
        "b": "Number of turns, type of wire, length of core, and cross-sectional area of core",
        "c": "Type of core material, number of turns, cross-sectional area of core, and length of core",
        "d": "Type of core material, type of wire, number of turns, and cross-sectional area of core",
        "answer": "Type of core material, number of turns, cross-sectional area of core, and length of core"
    },
    {
        "question": "An inductor is in series with a voltage source, an open switch, and a resistor. The instant the switch is closed, the inductor acts like\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "a short",
        "b": "an open",
        "c": "a resistor",
        "d": "a voltage source",
        "answer": "an open"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the phase angle between the source voltage and current, when a 100 mH inductor with a reactance of 6 k ohm, and a 1 k ohm resistor are in series with a source?\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "0.1 degrees",
        "b": "9.0 degrees",
        "c": "61.0 degrees",
        "d": "81.0 degrees",
        "answer": "81.0 degrees"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a load is not connected to the secondary of a transformer:\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "primary current is zero",
        "b": "primary current is inversely proportional to primary impedance",
        "c": "secondary voltage is zero",
        "d": "secondary voltage is proportional to primary impedance",
        "answer": "primary current is inversely proportional to primary impedance"
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary winding of a transformer is the side connected to the load.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "An air-core inductor has a metal core.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "The time constant of an inductive circuit is dependent on the circuit's resistance.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "The amount of dc current that an inductor will allow to pass depends on the circuit's total resistance that is in series with it.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "An inductor will boost current flow.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "A step-up transformer will have a turns ratio greater than 1.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "The secondary current in a transformer depends on the secondary voltage and load resistance values.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "Kirchhoff's voltage law does not apply to series RL circuits.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "Magnetic force is the force that produces a magnetic field.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "A magnet consisting of a coil of wire wound around a soft iron or steel core is called an electromagnet.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ideal inductor would not dissipate any energy.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "Five time constants are required for current in an inductor to reach a maximum value.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "The quality factor of an inductor is the ratio of inductive reactance to the winding resistance of the coil.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a dc circuit, the only conversion of energy to heat is in the inductance of the coil itself.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "Inductance is proportional to the cross-sectional area of a coil.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "tfq8_1023_1.gifThe primary and secondary are in phase.\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lenz's law states that the current induced in a circuit due to a change in the magnetic field is so directed as to oppose the change in flux or to exert a mechanical force opposing the motion.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "tfq8_1021_1.gifThe output of the secondary winding is 15 V.\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "For inductions in series, LT = L1 + L2 + L3 +...\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "Maximum power will transfer across a transformer when the primary impedance equals the secondary impedance.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "Increasing the inductance value in an ac inductive circuit will lower the circuit current.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "A magnetic field results whenever a current flows through a conductor.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "tfq11_1002_1.gifAll the schematic symbols shown in the given figure are variable inductors.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "Self-inductance is the property that causes an electromotive force to be produced in a conductor.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "tfq11_1004_1.gifThe total inductance in the given circuit is 0.6 mH.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "Inductors connected in series will increase the total inductance value.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "Inductors are not as versatile as capacitors.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "An ac generator will produce a constant waveform.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "The current through an inductor in a parallel RL circuit leads the current through the resistor.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "An RL filter could be a high-pass or a low-pass filter.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "Faraday's law states that the polarity of induced voltage in a coil is in opposition to the current change through that coil.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "A transformer can be designed to step up or step down dc voltage.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "",
        "d": "",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "After a voltage has been applied to an inductor, the current will be ___ of its full value after 2 time constants.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "63%",
        "b": "86%",
        "c": "95%",
        "d": "98%",
        "answer": "86%"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ___ of a coil is the inherent resistance of the wire.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "ac resistance",
        "b": "reactance",
        "c": "winding resistance",
        "d": "permeability",
        "answer": "winding resistance"
    },
    {
        "question": "fbq11_1008_1.gifThe inductive reactance of L2 is _____ in the given circuit.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "3.5 k ohm",
        "b": "4.4 k ohm",
        "c": "16.3 k ohm",
        "d": "23.3 k ohm",
        "answer": "4.4 k ohm"
    },
    {
        "question": "___ power represents the energy dissipated at a given point in time.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "True",
        "b": "Reactive",
        "c": "Real",
        "d": "Instantaneous",
        "answer": "Instantaneous"
    },
    {
        "question": "After the first time constant, a transient current has changed by _______________ %, leaving _______________ % remaining.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "63.2, 36.8",
        "b": "36.8, 63.2",
        "c": "13.5, 86.5",
        "d": "86.5, 13.5",
        "answer": "63.2, 36.8"
    },
    {
        "question": "fbq11_1008_1.gifThe total inductive reactance is ___ in the given circuit.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "3.5 k ohm",
        "b": "4.4 k ohm",
        "c": "16.3 k ohm",
        "d": "23.3 k ohm",
        "answer": "23.3 k ohm"
    },
    {
        "question": "fbq11_1002_1.gifThe inductance value of L3 in the given figure is _____ if the total inductance is 340 mH.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "150 mH",
        "b": "220 mH",
        "c": "295 mH",
        "d": "315 mH",
        "answer": "150 mH"
    },
    {
        "question": "When current flow tries to decrease in an inductor, the magnetic field _______________ and the voltage polarity across the inductor _______________.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "collapses, remains the same",
        "b": "expands, reverses",
        "c": "collapses, reverses",
        "d": "expands, remains the same",
        "answer": "collapses, reverses"
    },
    {
        "question": "Electromagnetic induction is the generation of _________ from __________.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "magnetism, electricity",
        "b": "electricity, electricity",
        "c": "electricity, magnetism",
        "d": "magnetism, magnetism",
        "answer": "electricity, magnetism"
    },
    {
        "question": "Inductive ___ represents the opposition to an alternating current.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "impedance",
        "b": "resistance",
        "c": "reluctance",
        "d": "reactance",
        "answer": "reactance"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ___ cannot change instantaneously in an inductor.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "voltage",
        "b": "current",
        "c": "power",
        "d": "magnetic field",
        "answer": "current"
    },
    {
        "question": "The opposition to ac by an inductor is directly proportional to ___.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "resistance",
        "b": "reactance",
        "c": "frequency",
        "d": "voltage",
        "answer": "frequency"
    },
    {
        "question": "An RL integrator can act as a __________ filter and an RC differentiator can act as a __________ filter.\r\n\r\n",
        "a": "high-pass, high-pass",
        "b": "low-pass, low-pass",
        "c": "high-pass, low pass",
        "d": "low-pass, high-pass",
        "answer": "low-pass, high-pass"
    }
]